WILMER RIVERA

Rome, GA

Phone: 706-331-4752 | Email: coding706@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/wilmer-rivera-0536291b3</u> | Portfolio:

https://wilmer88.github.io/blast-porfolio/

SUMMARY

Experienced working with Linux/Ubuntu, Windows and MACos, setting up different IDEs with various code editors like IntelliJ, Visual Studio and VS Code. Actively taking new courses on Pluralsight on OO design patterns. Strongly Committed to building reliable and maintainable code with any framework. Have successfully refactor projects with their newer version release. Have led all planning and designing of Coat & Code web Applications. Trusted by past Employers with company credit cards, vehicles, sensitive information, equipment, tools, materials and needed to aid a pending project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Softwares/Platforms: Django, Laravel, React, NoSQL, MongoDB, AWS, Oracle, Git, JQuery, Node,

handlebars.

Software Languages: ES6, JavaScript, Python, Java, PHP, C#, HTML5, CSS, C++

PROJECTS

Virtual-stand | github.com/wilmer88/taco-stand | https://taco-stand.herokuapp.com

- Gives business owners a template for their products and where foodies pre order, make online payments, eliminating waiting in line and the inevitable prepping wait time, also eliminates the need to have a person taking orders, receiving payments, the Check delivery time, since paid orders are instantly available to kitchen staff.
- A sole developer of ideas, the backend code, frontend design, and API architecture.
- Technologies used: React/JSX, React Router, Express, Node, MongoDB, Bulma, ES6, Bcrypt, JWT, Mongoose, Axios, Stripe Checkout, JSON Web Token and more, please see dependencies.

Web-Inventory | github.com/wilmer88/tool-inventory | https://tool-inventory.herokuapp.com

- App enables employees' mobile devices to document items, their locations, count, specifications, and the name of the employee that was assigned to count those items.
 Facilitating a speedy and accurate inventory count.
- Alone created, did the planning, came up with the ideas, the programming, the designing, the testing and launching of this application for mobile devices and/or desktop.
- Technologies: Foundation framework, HTML5, Handlebars, JawsDB MySQL, Sequelize.

ga_dev | github.com/wilmer88/err-help | https://ga-devs1.herokuapp.com

- Full Crud application where Jr developers can post their past errors. Answer unanswered errors. Created for jr developers to share knowledge and ask "dumb questions".
 Has had data migration and connects to a live database. The App is mobile responsive and also works well on desktop. Future development is pending until further notice.
- Lone creator of all backend and frontend code, the view all tab functionality, both edit and delete page functionalities are done. Please see my portfolio for my other projects.
- Project uses: Bootstrap, Django/MVC/ORM, SQLite3, pgAdmin, AWS, and Heroku.

EXPERIENCE

Owner

2020 - Present

Coat & Code LLC

Rome, Woodbine Ave

In charge of giving a price for job bids, budgeting and negotiating counter offers, analyzing and comparing offers to other alike jobs, for price matching; ensuring fair market price for both client Coat & Code. In charge of keeping communication with clients to better understand clients needs and expectations. Responsible for finished job quality and scheduling after job completion.

Generalist

2013 - 2020

MCC LLC

Rome, GA

Pipeline maintenance company that offers terminals, right of way and tank farms services. Was responsible for crew, equipment, trailers, transportation and equipment rentals. Driving different company box trucks, ordering and purchasing project materials and tools. Sandblasting, shoveling; painting underground lines on right of way, also doing interior construction, warehouse tasks and many other jobs and responsibilities. Gain massive respect when several property owners would go out of their way and hand write letters to the project manager, letting him know how happy and impressed they were with our work and how we went above and beyond expectations.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology: Atlanta, GA

2020 - 2020

An 18 week intensive Full Stack Flex Web Development Certification focused on gaining skills in frontend and backend web development, industry best practices, creating and connecting to databases, maintaining legacy code, computer science fundamentals and much more.